CURRICULUM VITAE

OMBUI KEANA HENRY

Tel: +254-707134655

Email:ombuiraphael80@gmail.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am an inspiring, talented, ambitious and hardworking individual of integrity in my area of expertise and lead by example through collective responsibility and teamwork. Furthermore, I am adept at handling multiple tasks on a daily basis competently and working well under pressure.

A key strength is communication; building strong relationships with people in order to deliver the best results. I enjoy working in a challenging environment that can provide me with major knowledge and skills required for my own career benefit and company goals achievement.

CAREER OBJECTIVES

To be a young, self-driven achiever in my field of work and study, willing to work beyond expectations to assist in the achievement of common goals. To work in a challenging environment that drives my urge to perform efficiently and that gives me a chance to embrace and learn from other people's achievements. To grow in my education field and gain skills to match the dynamic nature of my profession.

EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Aug 2016 – July 2022 : Kenyatta University

BSc. Electrical and Electronics Engineering.
Second Class Honors (Upper division)

Jan 2012 – Nov 2015 : Agoro Sare High School

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

A

Jan 2003 – Nov 2011 : Saoni Primary School

Kenya Certificate of Primary Education

B+

WORK EXPERIENCE

Oct 2022-Feb 2023: Technical Support Engineer, Faina Consultancy.

- PCB designing.
- Soldering.
- Creating Project Proposals.
- Compiling reports.

• Arduino programming.

Jan 2021 - Apr 2021: Electrical Engineer Attaché Nairobi Metropolitan services.

- Repair of breakdown machines.
- Installation and maintenance of streetlighting systems.
- Motor control and switching.
- Testing and management of generators.
- Creating technical reports.
- Ensuring all departments and services under the scope of engineering are well maintained, efficient and free from hazards.
- Replacement of fluorescent lamps.
- Domestic Installations.

Sep 2018 - Nov 2018: Electrical and Electronics Attaché, Kenyatta University

- Analysis of resistors, diodes, capacitors and inductors; their applications in electric circuits, importance and maintenance.
- Handle projects using optoelectronic devices such as photo resistors, photo diodes, phototransistors; their applications and maintenance.
- Smoothing out of DC voltage ripples to obtain a continuous signal from a rectified signal using a bridge rectifier and thyristor applications.
- Simulation of the audio amplifier circuit using proteus software, breadboard implementation and the soldering process
- Trouble-shooting
- Power transmission and motor operation.
- AC generators and brushless generator operation.
- Domestic installation; consumer unit design, one way switch, two-way switching, intermittent switches, three phase connection, socket connection and three phase motor connection design.
- Handling digital instruments and integrated circuits.
- Industrial switching
- Motor starting
- Automation

SKILLS

- Metal works: brazing, soldering
- Design: solid works, AUTOCAD
- Database management: SQL, MySQL
- Programming: MATLAB, C++
- Web development: HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Predictive learning using machine language
- Repair and maintenance of Electrical equipment
- Calibration of Electrical equipment

INTERESTS

Research and innovation

- Programming
- Traveling
- Performing analyses
- Database designing
- Web development

REFEREES

Please feel free to contact the under mentioned in regard to my competence, work ethic, performance and or any other aspect with respect to me:

Eng. Emmanuel Mwanik	Eng. Arthur Ogwayo	Dr. June Madete
Embedded Systems Engineer,	Head of Department,	The Chairperson,
Faina Consultancy,	Electrical and Electronics,	Electrical and Electronic
Tel: +254-706086296	Kenyatta University	Engineering Department Kenyatta University
mwanikmurray@gmail.com	Tel: +254-722291862	Tel: 0723525361
	Ogwayo.arthur@ku.ac.ke	
		madete.june@ku.ac.ke